So, my interest in self-driving cars started with
私が自動運転車に興味を持ったのは Stanford の私のチームが
the DARPA Grand Challenge in 2004 in which my team at Stanford developed Stanley,
2004 年の DARPA Grand Challenge
a robot that could drive itself through the Mojave Desert.
モハーベ砂漠を自走できるロボットを開発してからです
The vehicle was based on a Volkswagen Touareg,
車両はフォルクスワーゲンのトゥアレグをベースにしており
was equipped with all kinds of sensors,
GPS やレーザーなど
like GPS and laser.
さまざまなセンサーが取り付けられていました
It was able to make its own decisions without any human input whatsoever.
この車両は 人間の入力なしに 自分で決断することができました
The DARPA Grand Challenge was a government-sponsored race that took place in 2005.
DARPA グランド チャレンジは 2005 年に行われた政府主催のレースでした
Here, we see our robot, Stanley,
ここで 私たちのロボットである Stanley
moving through deserts completely without a human on board.
が 人間が乗っていなくても砂漠を完全に通り抜けていくのを見ています
The task was to drive a desert trail for about 130 miles.
タスクは 砂漠の道を約 130 マイル運転することでした
Whoever was fastest would win the race.
最速の人がレースに勝ちます
He look passing a different robot by
彼は、
Carnegie Mellon University about a 110 miles into the race.
約 110 マイル走って カーネギーメロン大学の近くで 別のロボットを抜かしたようです
Our robot was able to navigate with these steep,
ロボットはこの急な
mountainous roads and able to avoid collisions with rocks or falling down a cliff,
山岳道路を走行することができ 岩との衝突や崖からの落下を避けることができました
all based on its ability to use what I'm going to teach you in this class.
すべては このクラスで教えてくれるものを使う能力に基づいています
After almost seven hours and 131 miles,
約 7 時間が経過し 131 マイルに到達した時点で
everybody returned all the way to the starting base as
すべての人々は出発地点である スミソニアン歴史博物館に戻りました
the first robot to ever finish a DARPA Grand Challenge,
そこで DARPA グランド チャレンジを制した最初のロボットである Stanley を迎えました
winning Stanford University two million bucks,
このロボットは スタンフォード大学で 200 万ドルの賞金
and Stanley, a place in the Smithsonian Museum of American History.
を獲得しました
This work led to the Urban Challenge in which we build another robot called Junior,
この仕事は 2 位になった Junior と呼ばれる
that eventually took second place.
アーバン チャレンジにつながりました
The Urban Challenge was a follow-up raised by DARPA,
アーバン チャレンジは DARPA の続きで
which cars were asked to drive in traffic.
そこでは 車両を運転するよう求められました
So, whereas the Grand Challenge was kind of a motionless desert floor,
グランド チャレンジは動かない砂漠でしたが
this was a mock urban city where the Rover was able to
ローバーが他の交通車両と対話することができ
interact with other traffic and had to follow
左折した際に交通規則を守ることができる
traffic rules as in this left turn over here.
シミュレーションした市街地でした
Had to be able to stay on lanes with very high precision,
非常に高い精度で車線を走行しなければならず
accommodate oncoming traffic and just drive
接近中の交通に対応し
confidently in a situation that resemble the small city.
小さな町のような状況で自信を持って運転する必要があります
This led at Google to a sequence of experiments known as the Google self-driving car.
これがグーグルにおける グーグル自動運転車として知られている一連の実験につながりました
I believe these are the best robotic cars out there today.
私はこれらのロボットが 現在 最高のロボット自動車であると信じています
Here we see one of our Priuses on University Avenue in Palo Alto,
パロアルトのユニバーシティ アベニューを プリウスが 1 台走っています
undetected driving just like a human driver,
人間の運転手が運転しているように見えますが
but this car is driving by itself.
この車は自律的に運転しています
Our cars have been able to drive hundreds of thousands of miles,
私たちの車は何十万マイルも走ることができました
all across California and some of Nevada,
カリフォルニア全域とネバダの一部
in downtown areas like San Francisco,
サンフランシスコのような繁華街
on busy highways, here in Monterey,
モントレーのような交通量の多い高速道路
as well a coastal city in California with lots and lots of pedestrians.
たくさんの歩行者がいるカリフォルニアの沿岸都市などを走行しました
These are all completely self-driving moments where the car is
このビデオに示すように これは 完全に自走する瞬間であり
able to accommodate things like deers in the headlight in the middle of the night,
車は夜中にヘッドライトの鹿のようなものをとらえたり
or even crooked Lombard Street in San Francisco as shown in this video.
サンフランシスコの曲がったロンバード ストリートをとらえたりすることができました
This is what I'm doing on my day job.
これは私が日常 仕事にしていることです
I really love- with my team,
私は
building self-driving cars, we believe it's going to be change the world.
自動運転車の製造チームが大好きで 世界に挑戦し続けていくと確信しています
In this class, that's what I hope to enable you to do. So, let's dive in.
このクラスは 皆さんができるように願っていることを扱っていますでは 始めましょう